<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<data>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[20]]></id>
		<name><![CDATA[Cast Iron Tram Shelter]]></name>
		<lat><![CDATA[-37.870661]]></lat>
		<long><![CDATA[145.008623]]></long>
		<summary><![CDATA[This cast iron tram shelter, designed by the Prahran & Malvern Tramways Trust, and erected in 1917, is of State social, historic and aesthetic significance.
Socially and historically.]]></summary>
		<image_url><![CDATA[http://vhd.heritagecouncil.vic.gov.au/vhd-images/places/000/187/977.jpg]]></image_url>
		<postcode><![CDATA[3162]]></postcode>
		<description><![CDATA[This cast iron tram shelter, designed by the Prahran & Malvern Tramways Trust, and erected in 1917, is of State social, historic and aesthetic significance.

Socially and historically, this shelter is part of a group of 16 early tram shelters that survive in inner city and the middle ring suburbs that are together considered the most important and enjoyed items of historic street furniture in Melbourne. They are widely regarded as an essential part of the character of Melbourne as a 'tram city' and important historic elements of the tram system. They have provided shelter to many commuters over the years, and provided delight to the thousands of passers-by.

Aesthetically, the cast-iron shelters, of which there are three in Melbourne, are delightful examples of street architecture (the others, also classified, are in Kew, B7039, and Armadale B7051). They are modelled on the Melbourne City Council standard 19th century cast-iron verandahs, but lower, featuring Corinthian columns, and 'rinceau' pattern cast-iron friezes. Given the removal of most cast-iron verandahs in the suburbs, they are rare survivors.

Classified: 04/09/1975

Revised: 03/04/2000







Historically, they are a prominent reminder of the former Prahran & Malvern Tramway Trust, a municipal enterprise set up in the early years of this century, and are a design unique to that company. The three shelters remaining indicate the former extent of what was the largest independent electric tram network in the suburbs.]]></description>
		<address><![CDATA[S.E. Cnr Balaclava & Orrong Roads, CAULFIELD, GLEN EIRA CITY]]></address>
		<link><![CDATA[]]></link>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[26]]></id>
		<name><![CDATA[St Mary's Jubilee School]]></name>
		<lat><![CDATA[-37.880331]]></lat>
		<long><![CDATA[145.025658]]></long>
		<summary><![CDATA[A school designed by Charles Webb in 1887, with a charming belfry and banded Venetian window heads.
]]></summary>
		<image_url><![CDATA[http://vhd.heritagecouncil.vic.gov.au/vhd-images/places/000/189/975.jpg]]></image_url>
		<postcode><![CDATA[3162]]></postcode>
		<description><![CDATA[A school designed by Charles Webb in 1887, with a charming belfry and banded Venetian window heads.

Classified: 15/03/1973
]]></description>
		<address><![CDATA[Cnr Glen Eira Road & Hood Crescent, CAULFIELD, GLEN EIRA CITY]]></address>
		<link><![CDATA[]]></link>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[28]]></id>
		<name><![CDATA[Karl Duldig Ceramic Mural - Adam & Eve]]></name>
		<lat><![CDATA[-37.880029]]></lat>
		<long><![CDATA[145.023306]]></long>
		<summary><![CDATA[Karl Duldig's ceramic relief, "Adam and Eve" is significant at a local level.
With his ceramic bas reliefs, Karl Duldig was amongst the first sculptors in Australia to visualise and develop.]]></summary>
		<image_url><![CDATA[http://vhd.heritagecouncil.vic.gov.au/vhd-images/places/000/068/232.jpg]]></image_url>
		<postcode><![CDATA[3162]]></postcode>
		<description><![CDATA[Karl Duldig's ceramic relief, "Adam and Eve" is significant at a local level.

With his ceramic bas reliefs, Karl Duldig was amongst the first sculptors in Australia to visualise and develop the links between architecture and incorporated art.

Duldig's ceramic reliefs intend and attain an important technical and historical bridge between the appreciation and use of two and three dimensional art in society. Duldig's mural reliefs can almost be read as three dimensional paintings, and at the time of their execution, served to break down the barriers of the public appreciation of sculpture in Australia, as opposed to the then more recognised art form of painting.

The reliefs illustrate a highly developed skill and individuality in their construction and use of terracotta clay, and were a natural progression from his works in clay and ceramics after World War 11 in Australia. Thematically this work refers to and as also informed by the artist's European background and this specific biblical subject first appears in an early European carving ("Adam and Eve", 1912).

Recognition of Karl Duldig as a sculptor and ceramic artist is acknowledged in his representation in the collections of the National Gallery of Australia, Canberra, and the National Gallery of Victoria, Caulfield Permanent Art Collection also holds other significant works by the artist.

After the destruction of Duldig's relief, "Progress of Man", 1960, at 505 St. Kilda Road, Melbourne, in 1991, this relief is one of only three to which the public has access in Melbourne.

Classified: 20/10/1993]]></description>
		<address><![CDATA[Munipical Offices, Cnr Hawthorn and Glen Eira Roads, CAULFIELD SOUTH, GLEN EIRA CITY]]></address>
		<link><![CDATA[]]></link>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[29]]></id>
		<name><![CDATA[Karl Dulgig Ceramic Mural - The Family]]></name>
		<lat><![CDATA[-37.880029]]></lat>
		<long><![CDATA[145.023306]]></long>
		<summary><![CDATA[Karl Duldig's ceramic relief, The Family is significant at a Local level.
It is the first of three ceramic reliefs to be completed by Karl Duldig in 1957.
The Family, was commissioned.]]></summary>
		<image_url><![CDATA[http://vhd.heritagecouncil.vic.gov.au/vhd-images/places/000/068/233.jpg]]></image_url>
		<postcode><![CDATA[3162]]></postcode>
		<description><![CDATA[Karl Duldig's ceramic relief, The Family is significant at a Local level.

It is the first of three ceramic reliefs to be completed by Karl Duldig in 1957.

The Family, was commissioned for a domestic setting to portray the family of the patron, however, its relocation to the Caulfield City Offices (as part of the City of Caulfield Permanent Art Collection) has been achieved with remarkable sympathy to the work. The work now stands as a public work of art, with wide appeal and of great interest to visitors as an excellent example of Duldig's work and its development.

For Karl Duldig, the family symbolised unity, peace and progress, and was the cornerstone of our society, with its structure and role essential for the well being of our future development. The reliefs illustrate a highly developed skill and individuality in their construction and use of terracotta clay, and were a natural progression from his works in clay and ceramics after World War 11 in Australia.

Recognition of Karl Duldig as a suclptor and ceramic artist is acknowledged in his representation in the collections of the National Gallery of Australia, Canberra, and the National Gallery of Victoria, along with other Regional Gallery collections in Australia and in collections overseas. The City of Caulfield Permanent Art Collection also holds other significant works by the artist.

After the destruction of Duldig's relief, Progress of Man, 1960, at 505 St. Kilda Road, Melbourne in 1991, this relief is one of only three to which the public has access in Melbourne.

Classified: 20/10/1993]]></description>
		<address><![CDATA[Municipal Offices, Cnr Hawthorn & Glen Eira Roads, CAULFIELD SOUTH, GLEN EIRA CITY]]></address>
		<link><![CDATA[]]></link>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[39]]></id>
		<name><![CDATA[Fairfield Hall]]></name>
		<lat><![CDATA[-37.900688]]></lat>
		<long><![CDATA[145.015545]]></long>
		<summary><![CDATA[Fairfield Hall, built in 1890 or 1892 and designed by architect George Jobbins, is significant at the regional level as an interesting suburban Boom period mansion that has survived .]]></summary>
		<image_url><![CDATA[http://vhd.heritagecouncil.vic.gov.au/vhd-images/places/000/068/277.jpg]]></image_url>
		<postcode><![CDATA[3162]]></postcode>
		<description><![CDATA[Fairfield Hall, built in 1890 or 1892 and designed by architect George Jobbins, is significant at the regional level as an interesting suburban Boom period mansion that has survived with relatively large grounds, and for including elaborate timber ceilings in all the main rooms. The classsification includes the grounds, driveway and gates, but it is not known if any of these are in original condition. The single storey house displays a range of architectural influences from the Boom period and includes distinguishing features such as bichromatic brickwork, a conical roofed projecting corner bay, and a prominent (but poorly proportioned) three storeyed tower. The timber ceilings are made up of red pine framing and kauri panels, now painted. As a Victorian mansion complete with tower and an extensive garden frontage to North Road in an area almost totally dominated by interwar houses, Fairfield Hall is a local landmark.

Classified: 04/08/1997]]></description>
		<address><![CDATA[225 North Road, CAULFIELD SOUTH, GLEN EIRA CITY]]></address>
		<link><![CDATA[]]></link>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[47]]></id>
		<name><![CDATA[Glen Eira]]></name>
		<lat><![CDATA[-37.882565]]></lat>
		<long><![CDATA[145.015646]]></long>
		<summary><![CDATA[Built c.1880.
Classified: 25/12/1963
Demolished c.1964]]></summary>
		<image_url><![CDATA[http://vhd.heritagecouncil.vic.gov.au/vhd-images/places/000/075/908.jpg]]></image_url>
		<postcode><![CDATA[3162]]></postcode>
		<description><![CDATA[Built c.1880.

Classified: 25/12/1963
Demolished c.1964
]]></description>
		<address><![CDATA[Kooyong Road CAULFIELD, GLEN EIRA CITY]]></address>
		<link><![CDATA[]]></link>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[48]]></id>
		<name><![CDATA[Hillcrest Estate - Historic Area]]></name>
		<lat><![CDATA[-37.886903]]></lat>
		<long><![CDATA[145.021979]]></long>
		<summary><![CDATA[The Hillcrest Estate, built 1933-34, is of significance as the first estate of Albert Victor Jennings (later knighted). Building on the principles and experience established in this .]]></summary>
		<image_url><![CDATA[http://vhd.heritagecouncil.vic.gov.au/vhd-images/places/000/190/860.jpg]]></image_url>
		<postcode><![CDATA[3162]]></postcode>
		<description><![CDATA[The Hillcrest Estate, built 1933-34, is of significance as the first estate of Albert Victor Jennings (later knighted). Building on the principles and experience established in this and another three estates developed in the depressed building industry of the 1930's, AV Jennings' company became Australia's largest private home order building, and the largest and most influential provider of house and land packages, during the post war suburban boom.

Classified: 01/01/1991]]></description>
		<address><![CDATA[Hillcrest Avenue & Manara Road, CAULFIELD SOUTH, GLEN EIRA CITY]]></address>
		<link><![CDATA[]]></link>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[76]]></id>
		<name><![CDATA[Former Primitive Methodist Church (South Melbourne)]]></name>
		<lat><![CDATA[-37.892664]]></lat>
		<long><![CDATA[145.046043]]></long>
		<summary><![CDATA[A timber Gothic church of American Carpenter Gothic Character, first built by the Primitive Methodist in South Melbourne in 1889, with decorative barge boards and spire. ]]></summary>
		<image_url><![CDATA[http://vhd.heritagecouncil.vic.gov.au/vhd-images/places/000/068/231.jpg]]></image_url>
		<postcode><![CDATA[3163]]></postcode>
		<description><![CDATA[A timber Gothic church of American Carpenter Gothic Character, first built by the Primitive Methodist in South Melbourne in 1889, with decorative barge boards and spire. The building was moved to Glenhuntly in 1909, since when the west gable window has been blocked.

Classified 15/03/1977
]]></description>
		<address><![CDATA[152 Grange Road, GLEN HUNTLY, GLEN EIRA CITY]]></address>
		<link><![CDATA[]]></link>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[79]]></id>
		<name><![CDATA[Beauville Estate- Historic Area]]></name>
		<lat><![CDATA[-37.89069]]></lat>
		<long><![CDATA[145.067589]]></long>
		<summary><![CDATA[The Beauville Estate, built 1934 - 6, was the second estate of Albert Victor Jennings (later knighted) whose company later became Australia's largest private home-order builder .]]></summary>
		<image_url><![CDATA[http://vhd.heritagecouncil.vic.gov.au/vhd-images/places/000/194/215.jpg]]></image_url>
		<postcode><![CDATA[3163]]></postcode>
		<description><![CDATA[The Beauville Estate, built 1934 - 6, was the second estate of Albert Victor Jennings (later knighted) whose company later became Australia's largest private home-order builder and the largest and most influential provider of house and land packages. It is of significance as the clear harbinger of the planned community developments which emerged in the post war decades.

Classified: 01/01/1991]]></description>
		<address><![CDATA[Beauville Avenue, Gloucester Court, Lindsay Avenue, Murrumbeena & Dalny Roads, MURRUMBEENA, GLEN EIRA CITY]]></address>
		<link><![CDATA[]]></link>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[90]]></id>
		<name><![CDATA[Former Harleston]]></name>
		<lat><![CDATA[-37.870661]]></lat>
		<long><![CDATA[145.008623]]></long>
		<summary><![CDATA[Harleston was built for Mr. F S Grimwade in 1875.
Classified: 13/02/1964]]></summary>
		<image_url><![CDATA[http://vhd.heritagecouncil.vic.gov.au/vhd-images/places/000/075/658.jpg]]></image_url>
		<postcode><![CDATA[3183]]></postcode>
		<description><![CDATA[Harleston was built for Mr. F S Grimwade in 1875.

Classified: 13/02/1964]]></description>
		<address><![CDATA[Cnr Balaclava Road & Orrong Road, ST KILDA EAST, GLEN EIRA CITY]]></address>
		<link><![CDATA[]]></link>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[97]]></id>
		<name><![CDATA[St Kilda East Congregation Church Honour Roll (First World War)]]></name>
		<lat><![CDATA[-37.86644]]></lat>
		<long><![CDATA[144.99999]]></long>
		<summary><![CDATA[This place is listed on the Victoria Heritage Database. Currently, no information is available, stay tuned for further updates]]></summary>
		<image_url><![CDATA[http://vhd.heritagecouncil.vic.gov.au/vhd-images/places/000/191/391.jpg]]></image_url>
		<postcode><![CDATA[3183]]></postcode>
		<description><![CDATA[This place is listed on the Victoria Heritage Database. Currently, no information is available, stay tuned for further updates]]></description>
		<address><![CDATA[Corner Hotham Street and Inkerman Street ST KILDA EAST, GLEN EIRA CITY]]></address>
		<link><![CDATA[]]></link>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[98]]></id>
		<name><![CDATA[St George Uniting Church Honour Roll (St Kilda East) (Second World War)]]></name>
		<lat><![CDATA[-37.86184]]></lat>
		<long><![CDATA[144.99161]]></long>
		<summary><![CDATA[This place is listed on the Victoria Heritage Database. Currently, no information is available, stay tuned for further updates]]></summary>
		<image_url><![CDATA[http://vhd.heritagecouncil.vic.gov.au/vhd-images/places/000/191/844.jpg]]></image_url>
		<postcode><![CDATA[3183]]></postcode>
		<description><![CDATA[This place is listed on the Victoria Heritage Database. Currently, no information is available, stay tuned for further updates]]></description>
		<address><![CDATA[4 Chapel Street ST KILDA EAST, GLEN EIRA CITY]]></address>
		<link><![CDATA[]]></link>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[123]]></id>
		<name><![CDATA[Bellecourt]]></name>
		<lat><![CDATA[-37.881008]]></lat>
		<long><![CDATA[145.014061]]></long>
		<summary><![CDATA["Beemery" at 85 Seymour Road, is an imposing ltalianate villa with arcaded asymmetrical facade built in 1891 for Charles Langdon. It has aesthetic, historical and social significance.

]]></summary>
		<image_url><![CDATA[http://vhd.heritagecouncil.vic.gov.au/vhd-images/places/000/031/075.jpg]]></image_url>
		<postcode><![CDATA[3185]]></postcode>
		<description><![CDATA["Beemery" at 85 Seymour Road, is an imposing ltalianate villa with arcaded asymmetrical facade built in 1891 for Charles Langdon. It has aesthetic, historical and social significance.



Its aesthetic value rests with the facade which is highly representative of a not uncommon villa form of the late Victorian period. Its historical value derives from its association with the Langdon family in Caulfield (compare "Rosecraddock", "Tarqua" and "Hengar"). Its social value derives from its ability to demonstrate a lifestyle in late Victorian Caulfield.



]]></description>
		<address><![CDATA[85 Seymour Road ELSTERNWICK, Glen Eira City]]></address>
		<link><![CDATA[]]></link>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[137]]></id>
		<name><![CDATA[Former State Savings Bank]]></name>
		<lat><![CDATA[-37.884724]]></lat>
		<long><![CDATA[145.004153]]></long>
		<summary><![CDATA[This place is listed on the Victoria Heritage Database. Currently, no information is available, stay tuned for further updates]]></summary>
		<image_url><![CDATA[http://vhd.heritagecouncil.vic.gov.au/vhd-images/places/000/068/226.jpg]]></image_url>
		<postcode><![CDATA[3185]]></postcode>
		<description><![CDATA[This place is listed on the Victoria Heritage Database. Currently, no information is available, stay tuned for further updates]]></description>
		<address><![CDATA[372 Glenhuntly Road, ELSTERNWICK, GLEN EIRA CITY]]></address>
		<link><![CDATA[]]></link>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[140]]></id>
		<name><![CDATA[Burreel]]></name>
		<lat><![CDATA[-37.886847]]></lat>
		<long><![CDATA[145.014782]]></long>
		<summary><![CDATA[This is a large and substantially intact example of the grand villas of nineteenth century Melbourne.
The bulk of the house most probably was built in 1866-1868 for Francis John Sidney.]]></summary>
		<image_url><![CDATA[http://vhd.heritagecouncil.vic.gov.au/vhd-images/places/000/068/248.jpg]]></image_url>
		<postcode><![CDATA[3185]]></postcode>
		<description><![CDATA[This is a large and substantially intact example of the grand villas of nineteenth century Melbourne.

The bulk of the house most probably was built in 1866-1868 for Francis John Sidney Stephen, a prominent and highly regarded Melbourne solicitor and a member of an illustrious legal family. Stephen conducted a lucrative private practice and in 1845 was appointed first solicitor to the City of Melbourne; a position he held until his death in 1895. He took an active part in the development of Caulfield and was Shire President in 1874 and 1877. He was a resident at Burreel from 1868 to 1882.

The house has evolved in stages, the rear wings possibly remaining from a house built during the 1850s. The existing ornate cast iron verandah was probably built between 1882 and 1888 during the residence of Richard Buckhurst Buxted, a notable boom period auctioneer and real estate agent. George Allan, the founder of Allan's music store, was another important occupier from 1888 to 1991.

Bureel's essentially residential quality has been retained and the interior has been well preserved.

The significance of this building does not rest in any single unusual outstanding architectural feature, or in its association with a particularly prominent member of society in the past, but rather in the consistent integrity of both the interior and exterior, which results in the survival of an outstanding example of this type of residential building and its associations with two notable citizens.

Classified:11/08/1990
]]></description>
		<address><![CDATA[331 Kooyong Road, ELSTERNWICK, GLEN EIRA CITY]]></address>
		<link><![CDATA[]]></link>
	</node>
	<node>
		<id><![CDATA[145]]></id>
		<name><![CDATA[Presentation Convent]]></name>
		<lat><![CDATA[-37.882579]]></lat>
		<long><![CDATA[145.004721]]></long>
		<summary><![CDATA[Typical of period but yet interesting for association with Horatio Beauchamp.
Classified 26/11/1970]]></summary>
		<image_url><![CDATA[http://vhd.heritagecouncil.vic.gov.au/vhd-images/places/000/099/803.jpg]]></image_url>
		<postcode><![CDATA[3185]]></postcode>
		<description><![CDATA[Typical of period but yet interesting for association with Horatio Beauchamp.

Classified 26/11/1970
]]></description>
		<address><![CDATA[28 Sandham Street, ELSTERNWICK, GLEN EIRA CITY]]></address>
		<link><![CDATA[]]></link>
	</node>
</data>
